Finding Aid for the Duane Lyman and Associates, Architects, Records, 1923-1975 (bulk 1952-1963)
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Duane Lyman and Associates, Architects, Records, 1923-1975
1952 - 1963
Mss. B75-3
Duane Lyman and Associates, Architects
3 boxes (1.5 linear feet)
Chiefly reflects the schools and other public buildings, office buildings, and church structures which were designed by Duane Lyman for clients in Buffalo and Western New York State.
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Duane Lyman and Associates, Architects, Records, 1923-1975 (bulk 1952-1963), are open for research.
Administrative Information
Acquisition Information
Guy H. Baldwin, the donor of the collection, was an associate of Mr. Lyman for many years at their offices at 505 Delaware Avenue; after Mr. Lyman's death in 1966 he continued the practice for a short time under the name of Lyman, Baldwin and Castle.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note / Historical Note
Duane Lyman was born in Lockport on September 9, 1886. He attended Lafayette High School in Buffalo, graduating in 1904, and then went on to study architecture and mechanical engineering at Yale University's Sheffield Scientific School, where he earned his degree in 1908. He spent several years studying in Europe before returning to Buffalo in 1913 to begin with the architectural firm of Lansing & Bley. After military service in World War I, Mr. Lyman became a partner with Lawrence H. Bley in an association which lasted approximately 20 years and resulted in the completion of many notable buildings, such as the Saturn Club, Buffalo Country Club, and several academic buildings at the State University of New York at Buffalo (Main Street campus).
Chronology
circa 1919 Lansing and Bley
circa 1919-1939 Bley and Lyman
1939-1967 Duane Lyman and Associates
1967-? Lyman, Baldwin and Castle
Scope and Content Note
This collection chiefly reflects the schools and other public buildings, office buildings, and church structures which were designed by Duane Lyman for clients in Buffalo and Western New York State. Included are proposals, plans, job descriptions, budget estimates, and photographs.
Arrangement
Organized into three series:
I. Proposals and Job Description Booklets, 1950-1963
II. Photographs
III. Miscellaneous, 1911-1975.
Container List
- Booklets, 1950-1963, I.
  I is arranged chronologically.
  - Record of present and proposed Junior High, Senior High and Central High School Buildings, 1950-1960, (with duplicate)
  - Junior High, Senior High and Central School Buildings, 1950-1963, (with two duplicates)
  - Record of Present Elementary Work, 1955-1962
- Proposals 1951-1954, 1960, II.
  II is arranged alphabetically.
  - Police Stations for City Police Department, Buffalo, New York. June 6, 1952
  - Watkins Glen Elementary School and Other School Building Data, October 13, 1952, (with 2 duplicates)
  - Trumanburg Building Program, October 27, 1952
  - Fire Stations for Buffalo Fire Department, November 10, 1952
  - The Texas Company, Buffalo, New York, Administrative Office Building, December 24, 1952
  - Elementary School #26 for Benjamin C. Willis, Superintendent of Schools, Board of Education, Buffalo, New York, 1951-1953
  - Proposed Cornell Aeronautical Office Building and Laboratory, March 31, 1954
  - Police Station Modernization Program, Buffalo, New York, 1952-1953
  - Proposed Senior High School, Canandaigua City School District Canandaigua, New York, May 10, 1960
- Job Description Booklets 1923-1940, 1954-1955, 1974-1975, III.
  III is arranged chronologically.
  - Parish Hall, Trinity Evangelical Lutheran Church, Wellsville, New York, August 10, 1953
  - St. Paul's Evangelical Lutheran Church, North Tonawanda, New York, March 30, 1954
  - Westminster Church, April 13, 1954
  - Proposed Cornell Aeronautical Office Building and Laboratory, April 22, 1954
  - Saint Matthias Episcopal, East Aurora, New York, April 22, 1954
  - Riverside Baptist Church, Buffalo, New York, May 14, 1954
  - Board of Education, Newark, New York, June 15, 1954
  - Report to the Citizens Committee, Hammondsport Central School Hammondsport, New York, October 27, 1954
  - Fire Station Modernization Program, Buffalo, New York, November 18, 1954
  - Proposed Junior Senior High School, Alden, New York, January 12, 1955
  - Lutheran School for Lutheran Education Association of the Tonawandas, February 15, 1955
  - Macalpine Presbyterian Church, Buffalo, New York, May 13, 1955
  - Salem Evangelical and Reformed Church, Tonawanda, New York, October 14, 1955
  - Saint Matthews Evangelical Lutheran Church, Tonawanda, New York, November 9, 1955
  - Report on Modernization Program for the Home for the Friendless, 1500 Main Street Buffalo, New York, December 5, 1955
  - Immanuel Lutheran Church, Tonawanda, New York, undated
  - Fire Station Modernization Program, Buffalo, New York, undated, (with duplicate)
  - State of New York Standard School Plan Type B-1, One Story Junior High School 800 Expandable to 1000 Students, Report, undated, (with duplicate)
  - Alphabetical Job Listings, Guy H. Baldwin, Architect, undated, (70 pages)
  - Job Cost Record, circa 1923-1940, (oversized, in flat file)
  - Semi-Annual Schools Cost Report and Statistical Data, September 1974 to March 1975
    Includes Summary of Costs per Square Foot, March 1975, 3 pages
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
Lyman, Duane S., 1886-1966; Buffalo History Museum
Subject Terms
Lyman, Duane S., 1886-1966--Archives; Architects--New York (State)--Buffalo; Architecture--New York (State)--Buffalo; Buffalo History Museum--Archives
Genre Terms
Photographs